export const quiz = [
  {
    question: 'Who directed the movie "Interstellar"?',
    options: [
      'Steven Spielberg',
      'Quentin Tarantino',
      'Christopher Nolan',
      'Martin Scorsese',
    ],
    answer: 'Christopher Nolan',
  },

  {
    question: 'In what year was the movie "Titanic" released?',
    options: ['1995', '1998', '1997', '2000'],
    answer: '1997',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which actor played Jack Sparrow?',
    options: ['Johnny Depp', 'Orlando Bloom', 'Brad Pitt', 'Hugh Jackman'],
    answer: 'Johnny Depp',
  },

  {
    question:
      'How many parts does "The Lord of the Rings" (main trilogy) have?',
    options: ['4', '3', '5', '2'],
    answer: '3',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which film won the Oscar for Best Picture in 2020?',
    options: ['Parasite', '1917', 'Joker', 'Once Upon a Time in Hollywood'],
    answer: 'Parasite',
  },

  {
    question: `In which movie does the hero say the phrase: "I'll be back"?`,
    options: ['The Matrix', 'The Terminator', 'Predator', 'The Avengers'],
    answer: 'The Terminator',
  },

  {
    question: 'Who played Harry Potter?',
    options: [
      'Tom Holland',
      'Elijah Wood',
      'Daniel Radcliffe',
      'Timothée Chalamet',
    ],
    answer: 'Daniel Radcliffe',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which animation won the Oscar in 2022?',
    options: ['Encanto', 'Soul', 'Luka', 'Puss in Boots'],
    answer: 'Encanto',
  },

  {
    question:
      'In which city does the action of the movie "Joker" (2019) take place?',
    options: ['Chicago', 'Gotham', 'New York', 'Los Angeles'],
    answer: 'Gotham',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which film is the first in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?',
    options: ['Iron Man', 'Hulk', 'Avengers', 'Thor'],
    answer: 'Iron Man',
  },

  {
    question: 'Who played the lead role in the movie “Drive”?',
    options: ['Ryan Gosling', 'Christian Bale', 'Paul Walker', 'Tom Hardy'],
    answer: 'Ryan Gosling',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which Batman movie was directed by Matt Reeves?',
    options: [
      'The Dark Knight',
      'Batman Begins',
      'Batman (2022)',
      'Batman v Superman',
    ],
    answer: 'Batman (2022)',
  },

  {
    question: 'Who played Laura in “Logan”?',
    options: [
      'Scarlett Johansson',
      'Daphne Keene',
      'Millie Bobby Brown',
      'Florence Pugh',
    ],
    answer: 'Daphne Keene',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which cartoon is the sequel to “Monsters, Inc.”?',
    options: [
      'Toy Story 3',
      'Monsters University',
      'Braveheart',
      'Laughingstock',
    ],
    answer: 'Monsters University',
  },

  {
    question: 'In which movie is the hero stuck on the same day?',
    options: ['Groundhog Day', 'Inception', 'Time Lapse', 'The Matrix'],
    answer: 'Groundhog Day',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which country made the movie “Parasite”?',
    options: ['Japan', 'China', 'South Korea', 'Thailand'],
    answer: 'South Korea',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which actor played Darth Vader (voice)?',
    options: [
      'Marlon Brando',
      'Christopher Lee',
      'James Earl Jones',
      'Ian McKellen',
    ],
    answer: 'James Earl Jones',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which movie is NOT part of the “Back to the Future” trilogy?',
    options: [
      'Back to the Future 4',
      'Back to the Future 2',
      'Back to the Future 3',
      'Back to the Future',
    ],
    answer: 'Back to the Future 4',
  },

  {
    question: 'Who played the lead role in the movie “John Wick”?',
    options: ['Keanu Reeves', 'Jason Statham', 'Vin Diesel', 'Nicolas Cage'],
    answer: 'Keanu Reeves',
  },

  {
    question: 'What is the name of the actor who played Gandalf?',
    options: [
      'Patrick Stewart',
      'Bill Nighy',
      'Ian McKellen',
      'Christopher Plummer',
    ],
    answer: 'Ian McKellen',
  },

  {
    question: 'What animal saves the main character in “Life of Pi”?',
    options: ['Tiger', 'Bengal tiger', 'Lion', 'Panther'],
    answer: 'Bengal tiger',
  },

  {
    question: 'What movie has the tagline: “Why so serious?”',
    options: ['The Dark Knight', 'Inception', 'Joker', 'Justice League'],
    answer: 'The Dark Knight',
  },

  {
    question:
      'What movie is the highest-grossing movie of all time (as of 2024)?',
    options: ['Avatar', 'Avengers: Endgame', 'Titanic', 'Fast and Furious 7'],
    answer: 'Avatar',
  },

  {
    question: 'In which movie does the character “Gru” appear?',
    options: [
      'Despicable Me',
      'The Incredibles',
      'Ralph Breaks the Internet',
      'Minions',
    ],
    answer: 'Despicable Me',
  },

  {
    question: 'Who played the lead role in “The Truman Show”?',
    options: ['Jim Carrey', 'Tom Hanks', 'Robin Williams', 'Ben Stiller'],
    answer: 'Jim Carrey',
  },

  {
    question: 'In which movie is the character Forrest Gump?',
    options: ['Forrest Gump', 'Rain Man', 'The Grinch', 'Life is Beautiful'],
    answer: 'Forrest Gump',
  },

  {
    question: ' In which movie did Leonardo DiCaprio finally win an Oscar?',
    options: [
      'The Wolf of Wall Street',
      'Inception',
      'The Legend of Hugh Glass',
      'The Island of the Damned',
    ],
    answer: 'The Legend of Hugh Glass',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which studio produced the movie “Up”?',
    options: ['DreamWorks', ' Blue Sky', 'Pixar', 'Sony Pictures'],
    answer: 'Pixar',
  },

  {
    question: 'What weapon do Jedi use?',
    options: ['Lightsaber', 'Blaster', 'Spear', 'Plasma sword'],
    answer: 'Lightsaber',
  },

  {
    question: 'In which movie was Tom Holland’s debut as Spider-Man?',
    options: [
      'Avengers: Infinity War',
      'Spider-Man: Homecoming',
      'Avengers: Infinity ',
      'Spider-Man: No Way Home',
    ],
    answer: 'Avengers: Infinity War',
  },

  {
    question: 'What is the last name of the main character in The Matrix?',
    options: ['Anderson', 'Smith', 'Brown', 'Johnson'],
    answer: 'Anderson',
  },

  {
    question: 'What cartoon has the song “Let it Go” in it?',
    options: ['Moana', 'Rapunzel', 'Frozen', 'Encanto'],
    answer: 'Frozen',
  },

  {
    question:
      'How many films are there in the Harry Potter franchise (excluding Fantastic Beasts)?',
    options: ['7', '8', '6', '9'],
    answer: '8',
  },

  {
    question: 'What was the name of the boxer in Rocky?',
    options: ['Rocky Balboa', 'Jake LaMotta', 'Apollo Creed', 'Tommy Gunn'],
    answer: 'Rocky Balboa',
  },

  {
    question: 'Who played Tony Stark?',
    options: [
      'Robert Downey Jr.',
      'Chris Evans',
      'Benedict Cumberbatch',
      'Tom Holland',
    ],
    answer: 'Robert Downey Jr.',
  },

  {
    question: ' In which movie is the main character a clown?',
    options: ['It', 'Circus', 'Joker', 'The King of Comedy'],
    answer: 'Joker',
  },

  {
    question: 'Who voiced Shrek in the original?',
    options: ['John Cena', 'Mike Myers', 'Eddie Murphy', 'Robin Williams'],
    answer: 'Mike Myers',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which movie was based on a book by Stephen King?',
    options: [
      'The Shawshank Redemption',
      'Inception',
      'Green Book',
      'Requiem for a Dream',
    ],
    answer: 'The Shawshank Redemption',
  },

  {
    question: 'In which movie are the main characters toys?',
    options: ['Toy Story', 'Smeshariki', 'The Lego Movie', 'Pet Secrets'],
    answer: 'Toy Story',
  },

  {
    question: 'Which movie concluded the Avengers saga?',
    options: ['Infinity War', 'Endgame', 'Avengers', 'Age of Ultron'],
    answer: 'Endgame',
  },
];
